# Simon Cui (崔圣焕)

Phone 133-0125-6003

E-mail sunghwan.tsui@gmail.com

Working as China IT Manger 15+ years in the global IT team, in charge of Asia IT support. Skilled in creative problem solving, budget control, leading productive team, supporting growing business with reliable IT service, good relationship with internal customers.

## **Experience**

#### 2020-04 - present IT Manager, China&Japan/Data Analyst

Welocalize China

In addition to IT Support, started to take Data Analyst role, working with Matillion + Redshift + Power BI technology.

### 2010 - 2020-04 IT Manager, China & Japan

Welocalize China

Headed small team with 4 reports to support 300+ local users and 600+ desktops with 95% customer satisfaction rate, also supported global users from over 13 offices.

Budget and control cost around RMB1000K per year.

Supported Citrix Sharefile Cloud based file system.

Managed Windows 10 and Office 365 migration.

Managed to deploy VMWare ESXi + HP 3PAR + Veeam virtual environment.

Built C# Rest API Client Application to save 40 minutes for each production platform user configuration ticket.

Built Python + SQL Server +Power BI data integration to provide reports for Zendesk to save USD399 per month.

Built backup process for critical data with Symantec (Veritas) Backup Exec and HP Tape library.

Designed and Deployed Cisco Call Manger Express voice system in Beijing and Jinan.

Managed Symantec Endpoint Protection Antivirus system.

Migrated email system from IBM Lotus notes to Microsoft Exchange.

Setup and maintained Aspera file system.

Setup workaround solution for China specific Internet connection issue with VPN and proxy server.

#### 2005 - 2010 **IT Manager**

Transco Beijing Company Ltd.

Acquired by Welocalize in 2006, but IT system and team were kept unchanged until 2010.

Built helpdesk support process and developed helpdesk platform based on Lotus notes.

Built IT infrastructure from beginning for totally new office in Jinan.

Managed Site to Site VPN with Cisco ASA firewalls.

Setup Linux based ntop server to monitor network usage.

Experienced in Windows Server, Active Directory, DHCP administration.

Internal ISO Auditor for ISO9001

#### 2003 - 2005 Software QA / IT Application Developer

Transco Beijing Company Ltd.

Auto CAD software testing and localization.

Developed workflow system to support localization project processes. Experienced in VBScript, sed, Perl.

## **Education**

# 1997 - 2001 Northern Jiaotong University (Beijing Jiaotong University)

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

## **Certificates**

2020